# 广西·柳州
Liuzhou city, Guangxi province, China
# 螺蛳粉
river snails rice noodle
# 开始添肉了
time to fill the pot with meat
# 都不要辣
no spicy chili please
# 我不要酸笋 有一份不要酸笋
give me one without sour bamboo shoots please
# 不要辣
no spicy chili please
# 一碗中辣 一碗加辣
one medium spicy, and one heavy spicy
# 来这家店比较有意思的一个地方就是
one interesting point about this street restaurant is that
# 还未靠近这家店
before you approach to it,
# 就能够闻到螺蛳粉的味道
you can smell the taste of river snails rice noodle.
# 就是那种酸酸的味道  是酸笋的味道
it's a sour taste, derived from sour bamboo shoots.
# 这边的螺蛳粉是小碗的7块钱
a small bowl costs you 7 RMB
# 大碗的8块钱
while a big bowl costs 8 RMB.
# 咱们要的这一盆就是8块钱的大碗的
Here I ordered a big bowl that costs me 8 RMB.
# 这家店有个比较特色的地方就是
one characteristic about this restaurant is that
# 这边摆了很多的卤味
it provides lots of stewed food.
# 可以自己加像鸡脚 鸭脚
accompany with your noodles, you can order chicken feet, duck feet,
# 牛肚 牛肺 还有鸡蛋 豆腐这些
Beef belly, beef lungs, eggs, tofu, etc.
# 这些东西选完放在一个盆里
You put what you want into a bowl
# 然后老板再另算钱
then pay money for them
# 刚才还没有拍食物的时候
Before we film the food
# 我偷偷地尝了一下酸豆角
I secretly tried the sour beans
# 蘸了这个汤汁 真的是
Dip in this soup, it's really...
# 酸辣的味道特别想让人流口水
The sour and spicy taste really makes you drool.
# 我觉得这个螺蛳粉 比起我们以前吃的来说
I think the river snails rice noodle in the restaurant, compared to my previous experience,
# 它的味要更重一些
is heavier taste.
# 这个重不仅体现在汤底 比较浓
Not only the soup is relatively thick and heavy
# 红油多一些
the chili oil is more,
# 而且还有一点就是酸度上
but also the sour taste
# 也要更酸一些
is heavier.
# 我已经和老板说 要微辣了
I've told the restaurant owner to give me a slightly spicy one
# 微辣 还是很辣的
The slightly spicy is also relatively spicy
# 你看
look
# 这个汤底
in this pot
# 红油特别多 而且明显
there is lots of chili oil, it's evident
# 我发现
I found that
# 他们这边的螺蛳粉 都会加这种脆的花生
river snails rice noodle here is always accompanied by crispy peanuts.
# 花生刚进来的时候 是热的 脆脆的口感
When added into the noodle, peanuts are hot and crispy
# 只不过说 现在泡一泡 会软一些
but after a while in the noodle soup, it gradually turns soft.
# 这碗螺蛳粉里 花生 还有酸豆角 酸笋
more peanuts, sour beans and sour bamboo shoots
# 这些都是可以随便加的
are available for free.
# 不要忘了 我们还有这么多的卤味
Don't forget, we also ordered so much stewed food.
# 卤味 像猪蹄 鸭脚 鸡脚
Those stewed food, say trotters, duck feet, chicken feet
# 包括虎皮鸡蛋
and tiger-skin-like eggs,
# 都是先炸再卤 特别入味
is made by frying then stewing with spices.
# 浸透汁水的感觉 看起来就有食欲
soaked in the soup, it looks so appetizing.
# 你看这个皮 上面都是有一些褶皱的
look at the skin, there are some wrinkles on it,
# 特别吸收汤汁
which helps to absorb the soup.
# 可能鸡脚看起来会比较明显一些
those wrinkles on chicken foot are more visible.
# 这个鸡脚又辣又香
The chicken foot tastes spicy as well as fragrant
# 真的是放在嘴里 一抿就化
put it into your mouth. once sipped, it melts.
# 吃完了 我觉得螺蛳粉给我最大的印象在于
I finish it. the biggest impression the river snails rice noodle leaves to me is that
# 量大 实惠 而且这一碗红红绿绿
it's enough but cheap
# 特别好看
and it looks so good.
# 真是瞅一眼 就觉得 哇 好好吃
once you see it, you'll wow and imagine its delicious taste.
# 咱们来的时候还是白天
it's daytime when we arrived,
# 吃完饭 已经是黑夜了
now we finish the deal, it's already dark.
# 这个队 还是这么长
Look at the line, it's still so long.
# 要是晚来一会儿 我肯定就吃不上了
If I came here a little bit late, I wouldn't be served so quickly.
# 关 注
# 雪 鱼 探 店
Please Subscribe our channel Chinese Street Food.